all right everybody Nets a toy we're
going to demonstrate how to print
command line arguments to the screen and
to do that we or we can use our
variables over here and we can display
the number of parameters to the screen
and as well as the actual parameters and
parameters or a set of commands or data
that you pass your program for example
if we're to come over to the console and
say run our program we can pass it
strings like X Y 1020 or Flags
if we want things like that those are
the command line arguments passed to a
program so we can see how to get print
out the number of parameters we or pass
to a program as well as print out the
individual X Y 1 24 30 and so on and so
on
alright so now we have to of course use
order our stack frame to be able to make
references to the parameters pass onto a
program and as well as the local crap
local variables we declare and if you
remember we talked about the stack in
detail in my previous videos but real
quick the stack looks like this where
you have positive offset of for making
references to parameters so the first
one is +8 the second one is plus 12 and
so if we come over here we will see that
here EBP plus eight is pointing to the
command-line arguments of the number of
parameters passed so program as well as
EBP plus twelve planning to the address
that contains all the strings that were
passed to our program ok so I should
mention that I moved the value of 0 into
the register CX register which is the
counter register now one and I'm doing
this because we're going to be using a
loop to display all the parameters
passed our program because it can get
very tedious to have to repeat the same
instructions over and over again so
using a loop makes it more efficient so
we write less code
and do more things and this is the
structure of our loop and here is going
to be the body of our loop so I made a
label for the loop and this of course
labels are memory addresses and I'm
going to say I'm going to compare the
council register of 0 compared to the
number of parameters here in this case
we're going to be passing five
parameters and we're going to compare
those two values and if it's not equal
so in other words if 0 is not equal to 5
it'll jump here and then we'll just keep
increasing the value of the counter
register inside of the loop so that each
time it adds 1 to it each time all right
so of course this is the body of our
loop prior to calling external functions
or even calling your own functions it's
a good habit to get into by preserving
the registers that you're depending on
because we're depending on the BX
register holding the address of our list
of parameters and because we're
depending on the ax register holding the
number of parameters pass well program
and because we're use accounting on the
CX register as being the counter for
loop we want to make sure that we
preserve those values on the stack
before calling external functions
because the printf function will modify
some of these registers and to cover
ourselves we want to push these values
on the stack and then call the printf
function and then what the printf
function is done we want to pop the
stack back into the registers but notice
how we're popping it in reverse order
and then we can go ahead and call the
printf function alright so here we're
calling the printf that statement with
the address contained inside of the BX
register and then now we're going to be
proud
displaying the message arguments
reserved and we're calling the printf
function now this is something new that
I haven't been doing it in my previous
videos we're adding eight to the stack
pointer and as you know the stack goes
down towards memory it's constantly
going down so to clean up the stack you
need to add 8 to bring it back up
towards positive memory and so this is
important because how do we if we don't
have this statement right here this will
not this program will not run correctly
because the stack would be corrupted for
example here I'm pushing for binds and
here I'm pushing 4 bytes so in total I
pushed 8 bytes and so therefore I need
to add 8 to stack pointer to clean it up
so the last thing we want to do is now
to increase our counter by 1 after we
have restored the values pushed onto the
onto the stack after we restore the
values we want to increase them by 1 and
as well as increase the address that
contains a list of parameters by 4 so we
move to the next one and so after that
we can go ahead and compile a program
first of all let's go ahead and display
what my script looks like to compile
this program
so this is the beginning
and
it comes down over here after it's
compiled successfully we go ahead and
call our program and we pass it all you
man 1 2 3 & 4 but as well on but there's
actually five because the program name
is included so this is what's going to
be displayed to the screen so let's go
ahead and compile I'm running so as you
can see we compile and run our program
and this was a result the program name
is displayed as the first one that we
print out argument 1 2 3 & 4 and then
the program terminates so that's how we
display comment on arguments to the
screen please rate and subscribe thank
you